{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following strain(s), that grow in the jellies and candid fruits, are able to grow in sugar concentration upto 67.5%?", "opta": "Aspergillus", "optb": "Penicillium", "optc": "Citromyces", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The immediate source of the flat sour bacteria is usually the", "opta": "plant equipment", "optb": "sugar", "optc": "starch", "optd": "soil", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ability of B. coagulans to grow in tomato juice depends upon the", "opta": "number of spores present", "optb": "the availability of oxygen", "optc": "the pH of the juice", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Flat sour spoilage of acid foods is caused by", "opta": "B. coagulans", "optb": "B. pepo", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "B. stearothermophillus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most important kind of chemical spoilage of canned foods is the hydrogen swell which is favored by", "opta": "increasing acidities of foods", "optb": "increasing temperature of storage", "optc": "imperfection in the tinning and lacquering", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The presence of viable non-spore forming bacteria in heat process canned foods indicates leakage of the container. Which of the following is responsible for the spoilage of leaky cans?", "opta": "Plant equipment", "optb": "Cooling water", "optc": "Highly acidic medium", "optd": "High sugar content", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sulfur stinker spoilage, caused by  is uncommonly found in", "opta": "low acid foods", "optb": "medium acid foods", "optc": "high acid foods", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Medium acid foods with a pH between 5.3 and 4.5 are likely to undergo", "opta": "flat sour spoilage", "optb": "putrefaction", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "TA spoilage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Canned sweetened condensed milk may become thickened by", "opta": "Bacillus species", "optb": "Clostridium species", "optc": "Micrococcus species", "optd": "Saccharomyces species", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The canned acid foods such as pineapple, tomatoes and pears have been found spoiled by C. pasteurianum. Such spoilage is more likely when the pH of the food is", "opta": ">4.5", "optb": "<4.5", "optc": ">5.3", "optd": "<5.3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following species can cause bitterness, acidity and curdling in canned milk, cream and evaporated milk?", "opta": "Bacillus", "optb": "Clostridium", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Saccharomyces", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Acid foods with a pH between 4.5 and 3.7 usually are spoiled by", "opta": "B. coagulans", "optb": "Saccharolytic anaerobe", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The butyric acid type of fermentation in acid or medium acid foods, with swelling of the container by the carbon dioxide and hydrogen gas is caused by", "opta": "C. butyricum", "optb": "C. pasteurianum", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "C. sporogenes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) is/are porteolytic or putrefactive decomposing proteins with the production of malodorous compounds such as H2S, mercaptans, ammonia, indole and skatole?", "opta": "C. sporogenes", "optb": "C. putrifaciens", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "C. butyricum", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Canned poultry is more often spoiled by", "opta": "putrefactive than by Saccharolytic Clostridia", "optb": "Saccharolytic Clostridia than by putrefactive", "optc": "Saccharomyces species", "optd": "Micrococcus species", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Canned meat and fish exhibit spoilage by", "opta": "Bacillus species", "optb": "Clostridium species", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Saccharomyces", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "High acid foods with a pH < 3.7 undergo spoilage by", "opta": "Saccharolytic anaerobe", "optb": "B. coagulans", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "do not undergo spoilage by microorganisms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The putrifactive anaerobes grow best in the", "opta": "low acid canned foods", "optb": "medium acid canned foods", "optc": "high acid canned foods", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "High acid foods with a pH above 5.3 are especially subjected to", "opta": "flat sour spoilage", "optb": "putrefaction", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "TA spoilage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}